♪
[COCO] Is an athlete
an athlete
from the moment they're born?
What about astronauts,
or pop stars?
You don't know what you'll be
until you've grown up.
So, is it the same for witches?
[footsteps]
[Coco sighs]
[wind blowing]
[Coco exclaims]
[sighs tiredly]
Oh! I'm making
a big mess, aren't I?
Sorry, I'm almost done.
Don't worry,
it'll go back to normal.
This spring is touched
by magic!
I'll never get tired of it.
Magic is so... amazing!
The world around us
is brimming with magic.
A blessing that improves
our lives in so many ways.
THE MAGIC
THAT STARTED EVERYTHING
But how it works
is a bit of a mystery.
The only ones who can
cast spells are witches.
[cattle bleating]
[COCO] All we ordinary people
can do is sit back
and enjoy the results.
But we can never use
magic ourselves.
I wish I had been born a witch.
Hm?
Oh, sheets of white,
become now a cloak of flight!
Uh...
[gasps] No, come back!
This isn't the kind
of flight I meant!
[gasps]
♪
[exclaims softly]
[Coco panting]
A Pegasus Carriage!
♪
[exclaims excitedly]
I've never seen one land!
I can't wait!
Mom, look!
There's a Pegasus Carriage!
Mom!
Mom, where are you?
Mom?
Oh...
[BOTH] Huh?
[QIFREY] Hm.
I'm sorry, sir!
I didn't know you were there.
It's quite all right.
It was my own fault.
A poor place to stand.
[WOMAN 1]
My word, I can't believe it!
Imagine, finding such a garment
all the way out here!
[WOMAN 2] Ah, yes, but isn't
wood-sorrel embroidery
a tad dated?
Oh, look at this!
-Genuine Harrian lace!
-[both gasp]
[WOMAN 2] Amazing! The stock
in the castle town
-sold out almost immediately.
-[Coco exclaims]
-[indistinct chatter]
-It must have been them!
They came
in the Pegasus Carriage!
-[women chuckle]
-Oh. No, I'm not with them.
Pardon me, but do you perhaps
have any more lace like this?
[COCO'S MOM]
Oh, of course, ma'am.
I'll be right with you!
Coco? I could use your help!
[WOMAN 3] How about this one?
What can we do for you, sir?
I was looking for some
smoke-colored fabric.
But I can come again.
I could cut it for you
if you like!
Will you, now?
You're in good hands with her!
-I see.
-[indistinct chatter continues]
[gasps excitedly]
When I'm done,
can I go see
the Pegasus Carriage?
Go see the what?
There's a Pegasus Carriage
outside!
Oh, for goodness' sake.
We've talked about this.
No meddling
with the customers' property.
[COCO] I'll only look,
I promise!
[Coco's mom sighs]
[COCO] I'll stop talking about
how I want to be a witch
all the time. Please?
[COCO'S MOM] Mm...
-[indistinct chatter continues]
-[Coco's mom sighs]
All right, fine, but
only after you've finished.
[gasps excitedly] Thank you.
Sorry to keep you waiting!
What measurements did you need?
-[QIFREY] Oh, here they are.
-I'll be right back.
♪
[inhales, blows softly]
[sighs]
[COCO] Uh?
[Coco whimpers]
My...
You have excellent focus
and steady hands.
No hesitation in the line.
Clean cut.
And a finish showing
precision and care.
I had no idea
this village possessed
such a skilled artisan.
This is real magic.
[Coco gasps]
[shrieks] No! What I do here
isn't anything like magic!
Magic is mysterious,
and priceless,
and wonderfully shiny
and sparkly,
and unbelievably beautiful!
It's just so... so precious,
more precious than I can say.
Actually, come to think of it,
what am I saying?
I'm getting the sense
you truly love magic.
Why is that? Tell me.
[Coco sighs]
[COCO] When I was little,
my mother took me
to a festival at the castle.
And while I was there,
I met a witch wearing a mask.
[♪ mysterious music playing]
[WITCH] You there, child.
Would you like to buy
a magic picture book?
Magic?
I love picture books,
but I've never heard of magic.
[WITCH] Why, magic is a miracle
that makes this world vibrant.
A Pegasus Carriage in the sky,
a spring with waters
ever crystal clear.
Even the cobblestones underfoot,
glowing brightly with each step.
All of these things are magic.
[gasps delightedly]
So pretty!
Wow, magic is the best!
Thank you, I love magic!
[WITCH] Buy the book
and get this wand for free.
♪
Really? That's what you spent
the money on?
I thought you wanted to get
some roasted strawberries.
I did! But then
I followed a butterfly,
and I found a person
wearing a pointed hat!
Yes, so you told me
once already.
And now, I have
a magic picture book!
And a wand too!
[Coco's mom chuckles]
All right, then.
It's getting late, Coco,
we should start heading home.
-[COCO] Mommy!
-Hm?
When I grow up,
I'm going to become a witch
and use my magic
to make the whole world vibrant,
just you wait!
You can't.
But why not?
Darling, you can't simply decide
to become a witch and use magic.
It's a power
you have to be born with.
Unfortunately, it's not
something ordinary people
are capable of.
Now, if you're ready,
let's go home.
But look! The ground shines
wherever I step!
[COCO'S MOM] Uh...
[both chuckle]
[COCO'S MOM] Well, let's see
if it keeps on shining
all the way home.
If so, maybe
you can use magic.
[Coco exclaims softly]
Ever since, it's been my dream
to become a witch,
and I can't seem to let it go.
I'd be interested in hearing
a bit more about the...
[loud thud]
-[WOMAN 3] Oh, my...
-[WOMAN 2] What was that?
[COCO'S MOM] Coco?
-[MAN] Whoa there, settle down.
-[horses neighing]
Steady. Steady!
[all gasp]
[cattle bleating]
Great, now look what you did.
[TANERL] Shut up. Ow...
[COCO] Are you all right?
-Coco.
-[COCO] What happened?
We didn't do anything.
It just suddenly fell apart.
No, it didn't, liar!
It fell because you crawled
underneath it!
[TANERL] You snitch!
He hit his head
while he was down there.
And it fell over.
[WOMAN 3]
No! This is absolutely terrible!
-[gasping]
-What have you done
to our Pegasus Carriage?
[WOMAN 2]
It belongs to my father!
We are so sorry!
I'm sure these boys feel awful
for troubling you.
How does your apology help us?
Without a carriage,
we can't return home!
[COCO'S MOM]
Oh, dear me, what can we do?
[QIFREY] Pardon me.
Perhaps I could be of service.
I took a look,
and the damage doesn't appear
to be serious.
Really? And who are you?
Apologies, allow me
to cap off my attire.
[Coco gasps]
[gasps]
Qifrey the witch,
at your service, madam.
[BOTH] A pointed hat.
You can fix it, then?
[QIFREY] Indeed.
[MAN] You certainly are
a lifesaver, Sir Witch!
[QIFREY]
It's nothing at all.
Why, I'll simply need to reapply
the spell
to the floorboard
of the carriage.
Your help is appreciated!
And happily given!
However, this work
environment is a bit...
You can use our workshop,
we would be
-so honored and delighted!
-Coco!
What? We would, Mom,
wouldn't we?
I mean, he's an honest
to goodness witch.
This could be the chance
I've been waiting for,
to witness the very moment
a spell is cast!
[cattle bleating]
May I ask for your assistance?
I will need someone
to keep watch,
so I can cast
the spell in private.
No one must come in
under any circumstances.
Thank you.
Guess it was too much
to hope for.
Still, why can't we see
how it's done?
Magic is practiced
all over the world,
yet most of us don't have
the first clue how it happens.
Only witches know the secret.
The secret... Oh?
-[COCO] Where'd they go?
-[TANERL] Almost fell!
[gasps] What do you two think
you're doing?
[KAMLA] She caught us!
[TANERL] She doesn't matter.
We're fine.
Can we see into the room
from here?
-[COCO] Wait for me!
-Fine, but keep your voice down!
[COCO] Out of the way!
[all exclaim]
Man, talk about disappointing.
What a letdown.
[wind howling]
[Coco whimpers] What is this?
[Coco gasps]
[wind howling]
[COCO] I shouldn't!
But I really want to!
But I shouldn't!
[gasps softly]
♪
[Coco gasps softly]
[COCO] He's drawing.
Drawing magic?
With a pen?
The wand that I got that day.
Was it actually...
I see now.
Witches don't cast spells.
They draw them!
[QIFREY] That's that.
Coco, all finished here.
[Coco panting]
Coco?
[COCO] Oh, are you done?
[panting]
[horses neighing]
[bird squawking]
[Coco's mom sighs]
You know, I was starting
to worry there for a moment.
[COCO] Uh?
[COCO'S MOM]
Well, you're in love with magic.
You have been ever since
you were little.
So I thought you might ask
to leave home
-and go off with that witch.
-[Coco gasps]
[COCO'S MOM] I already lost
your father to illness.
If I had to face
losing you too,
I don't know what I'd do.
You never will, Mom!
I promise I won't ever
leave you all alone!
[COCO'S MOM] My goodness,
aren't you a sweet girl.
Thank you.
[COCO'S MOM] Hm?
-Mm... [chuckles]
-[giggles]
[both sigh]
Goodnight, Mom.
[COCO'S MOM] Goodnight, dear.
-Oh, Coco?
-Hm?
Never mind.
Sweet dreams.
You too.
[Coco sighs softly]
I thought you might ask
to leave home
and go off with that witch.
[Coco sighs]
[COCO] The patterns
in the picture book,
the free wand
that came with it...
They were more than
they seemed.
This is a magic pen!
[creaking]
[COCO] Forgive me, Mom.
I won't go anywhere, but...
I have to try it!
[pen scratching]
♪
[Coco breathes shakily]
[soft jingling]
[COCO] Huh?
[groans] Nothing happened.
Now that I think about it,
of course it wouldn't be
that easy.
♪
[Coco gasps]
[exclaims]
[gasps]
[COCO] It sparkled!
That must mean it worked!
I can't believe it!
I used magic!
I used actual,
real-life magic! [squealing]
So magic is drawn.
But I wasn't supposed
to see it!
Will I get into trouble
if he finds out?
Maybe I'll draw...
just one more.
♪
[QIFREY] A picture book.
How curious.
Why does it nag at me so?
[gasps] Could it be?
[Coco gasps] A fire spell!
Please stop burning,
please stop burning!
[sighs] That was too close.
And yet...
I think I'm starting
to get the hang of it.
Bigger ones are more powerful
than smaller ones.
And neatly drawn ones
last longer than sloppy ones.
But drawing them that big
and that neat isn't easy.
Although he certainly
made it look that way.
I know!
♪
[COCO] I was right.
It's a lot easier to be neat
when I trace the drawing
rather than copy it.
And done!
[Coco gasps]
♪
[QIFREY] What did you draw?
Tell me, Coco!
What spell did you draw?
I... I don't know.
I traced a pattern
from the book, and I...
-[COCO'S MOM] Coco?
-[Coco gasps]
[gasps]
[COCO] Mom?
Coco!
Mom, run!
[Coco's mom gasps, screams]
No, this isn't real.
[cries] Mom!
Mom!
-Mom! Mom!
-[QIFREY] Forbidden magic!
-Let go! I have to save my mom!
-Hold still!
-She's in danger because of me!
-I don't want to drop you!
[QIFREY] Stop it!
That spell is evil,
you mustn't... No!
-[Coco cries]
-[QIFREY] Coco!
[COCO] I'm here, Mom!
[wails] No!
♪
[cries] I'm sorry.
I didn't know.
[QIFREY] Of course you didn't.
It was all kept a secret
to prevent tragedies like this.
A special ink,
and a set of Casting Seals.
That's all one needs
for magic to be used.
Concealing that is
our One Great Rule.
And now that
you know the truth,
you must have
your memories erased.
[Coco gasps, cries]
Please don't! I can't forget.
If I do, then who'll save
my mom?
I'm afraid I couldn't say.
I don't know
what kind of magic it was,
but I can remember
all those drawings by heart!
And if all those memories
are lost, then my mom...
[Qifrey gasps] The picture book.
That's right.
If it came
from who I think it did,
then I finally have a link
to their whereabouts!
This girl's memories
are my only chance
to track them down!
You say you remember
the book by heart?
[COCO] Hm.
[QIFREY] And you recall
the page you copied?
[COCO] Hmm.
[gasps] If we had
the book I used,
I could show you
which seal I drew.
If we can find the one
that hurt my Mom,
do you think there's something
you could do for her?
[QIFREY] There is a chance.
[Coco cries] Mr. Qifrey,
please don't erase my memories!
I'm willing to do anything
to rescue my mother!
Will you keep our secret?
[COCO] I promise!
And are you willing to learn?
To learn... [gasps]
[QIFREY] Once you know
the truth, it cannot be undone.
And so, you must join
those trusted with the secret.
That is your way forward,
the only way.
-Coco, from now on...
-[gasps]
You will be a witch.
EPISODE 2:
THE SCHOOL OF THE GRASSLAND